Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we've got another lesson all about food and eating.
我是Catherine，今天我们有一节关于食物和用餐的新课。
So today we're going to talk about all the tools that we use when we're at the table.
所以今天我们要聊聊在餐桌上使用的所有工具。
So what we use when we're eating.
也就是我们吃饭时用的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue and when we come back, we'll talk about some
那么让我们听听今天的对话，等我们回来后再讨论一些
of these words and some of the great phrases you're learning today.
今天要学的单词和精彩短语。
Honey, can you set the table?
亲爱的，你能摆一下桌子吗？
Well, I'm sure.
嗯，当然。
What are we having for dinner?
我们晚餐吃什么？
Do I need to put anything out in particular?
我需要特别摆出什么东西吗？
Well, make sure to put out the pepper and salt shakers.
嗯，记得把胡椒和盐瓶摆出来。
I don't know if your brother is coming tonight, so set an extra place mat just in case.
我不知道你弟弟今晚会不会来，所以多摆一个餐垫以防万一。
Okay.
好的。
Should I use the fancy silverware?
我要用那套精致的银餐具吗？
Yeah, go ahead.
嗯，用吧。
Forks, spoons, and knives.
叉子、勺子和刀子。
I roasted some meat, so be sure to put out some steak knives as well.
我烤了些肉，所以一定要也摆上牛排刀。
I'll also set some cups and sauces for some coffee after dinner.
我还会摆些杯子和碟子，饭后喝咖啡用。
Honey, have you seen our soup bowls?
亲爱的，你看到我们的汤碗了吗？
They're in the cupboard where you keep the gravy boat and serving dishes.
在放肉汁壶和上菜盘的橱柜里。
Just be careful because the wine glasses are also there.
小心点，因为酒杯也在那里。
Oops.
哎呀。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at a couple of words in language takeaway.
现在让我们看看“语言要点”中的几个单词。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
So our first word is a very important one.
我们的第一个单词非常重要。
You might have heard it before.
你可能以前听过。
The word is silverware.
这个词是silverware。
Okay, silverware.
好的，silverware。
Now this means that it's usually made something that's made out of silver, right?
这通常指用银制成的物品，对吧？
It could be.
可能是。
Maybe traditionally it's made out of silver, but it doesn't have to be.
也许传统上是银制的，但也不一定。
You could have wooden silverware or other metals.
你可以有木制的银餐具或其他金属的。
It's basically the things that you use to eat food with.
基本上就是你用来吃饭的东西。
Okay, so we're going to take this as a category.
好的，所以我们把它当作一个类别。
There are all the tools that we use to eat food with.
就是所有我们用来吃饭的工具。
So for example, a fork is a part of a silverware.
比如，叉子是银餐具的一部分。
It's a kind of silverware, fork.
它是一种银餐具，叉子。
A fork is the one that you usually put in your mouth with a piece of lettuce or meat
叉子就是你通常用来把生菜或肉
or something.
之类的东西送进嘴里的那个。
Okay, so it's pointy.
好的，所以它是尖的。
It has like four little points.
它有四个小尖头。
Now the one that we use to have dessert or to have soup with, we call that a spoon.
我们用来吃甜点或喝汤的那个，我们叫它勺子。
A spoon, that's right.
勺子，没错。
So to eat yogurt or ice cream, you use a spoon.
所以吃酸奶或冰淇淋时，你用勺子。
And finally, to cut things, you use a knife.
最后，要切东西时，你用刀子。
Okay, so in the dialogue we saw the plural form, knives, but singular it would be knife.
好的，在对话中我们看到了复数形式knives，但单数形式是knife。
That's right.
没错。
And sometimes there are foods that are very, very hard to cut.
有时候有些食物非常难切。
For example, steak is very hard to cut because it's a tough meat.
比如，牛排很难切，因为它是一种坚韧的肉。
And so in that case, we use a steak knife to cut it.
所以在这种情况下，我们用牛排刀来切。
Okay, so we have a knife or a steak knife.
好的，所以我们有knife或steak knife。
Steak knife more specifically is used to cut meats.
牛排刀更具体地用于切肉。
All right, so these are three kinds or actually four kinds of silverware.
好的，所以这是三种，实际上是四种银餐具。
Of course, there are other kinds, but those are the most important.
当然，还有其他种类，但这些是最重要的。
After that though, we have something that's important for making your food taste better.
之后，我们还有让食物更好吃的重要东西。
So what if I want to add salt or pepper?
如果我想加盐或胡椒呢？
What are those things called?
那些东西叫什么？
Those are called salt and pepper shakers.
那些叫盐和胡椒瓶。
We saw them in the dialogue that we need to put out the pepper and salt shakers.
我们在对话中看到需要摆出胡椒和盐瓶。
So the little thing where you keep the salt is called a shaker.
所以装盐的小东西叫shaker。
That's right, because the action, the verb is to shake.
没错，因为动作，动词是to shake。
That means moving your hand up and down so some salt will fall out onto your food.
意思是上下摇动手，让盐撒到食物上。
Exactly.
正是。
So usually it's only salt and pepper that we keep in these things, in these little shakers.
所以通常只有盐和胡椒放在这些小瓶子里。
But apart from salt and pepper shakers and all the silverware we're putting out, we're
但除了盐和胡椒瓶以及我们摆出的所有银餐具，我们
also putting out some saucers because we're going to have coffee later on.
还会摆出一些碟子，因为之后要喝咖啡。
Okay, so this normally goes together with cups, cups and saucers, but everyone knows
好的，这通常和杯子一起用，杯子和碟子，但大家都知道
what a cup is.
杯子是什么。
What is a saucer?
碟子是什么？
So a saucer is this little plate that you put under the cup when you're having coffee.
碟子就是喝咖啡时放在杯子下面的小盘子。
So usually that's where you keep your spoon or maybe the little bag of tea.
通常那里放你的勺子或小茶包。
Okay, so a saucer is important because it also helps in case you spill some coffee or
好的，所以碟子很重要，因为如果你洒了些咖啡或
tea so the coffee or tea doesn't go on the ground, it goes on the plate.
茶，它也能接住，不让咖啡或茶洒到地上，而是流到盘子上。
Exactly.
正是。
So that little plate is called a saucer.
所以那个小盘子叫saucer。
Now where do we keep all the plates, all the silverware?
那么我们把所有盘子、所有银餐具放在哪里？
We usually keep them in a cupboard.
我们通常把它们放在橱柜里。
Okay, so you might want to say cupboard because it's cup, C-U-P-B-O-A-R-D.
好的，你可能想说“cupboard”，因为它是“cup”，C-U-P-B-O-A-R-D。
That's not right.
那不对。
The word is pronounced cupboard.
这个词的发音是“cupboard”。
Okay, so even though it may seem like you should pronounce cupboard, the correct pronunciation
好的，所以尽管你可能觉得应该读成“cupboard”，但正确的发音
is cupboard.
是“cupboard”。
Cupboard.
“Cupboard”。
And a cupboard, like you said, is usually in the dining room or the kitchen because
而“cupboard”，就像你说的，通常放在餐厅或厨房，因为
it houses, it keeps all of our plates and bowls and sometimes our silverware.
它存放着，它保存我们所有的盘子和碗，有时还有银器。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so actually in the cupboard we also have some other things, dishes.
好的，实际上在橱柜里我们还有一些别的东西，比如餐具。
Specifically we have a gravy boat in there.
具体来说，里面有一个肉汁船。
Okay, so I'm not even sure why they call it a boat, but a gravy boat is basically a special
好的，我甚至不确定为什么他们叫它“船”，但肉汁船基本上是一个特殊的
dish.
器皿。
It's like a tall bowl with a spout so you can pour it that keeps gravy.
它像一个带嘴的高碗，这样你可以倒出来，用来盛肉汁。
So gravy is like a liquid or a sauce that goes on top of meat or potatoes.
所以肉汁是一种液体或酱汁，浇在肉或土豆上面。
I guess it kind of looks like a boat.
我想它看起来有点像船。
Just imagine a boat, but inside it's empty.
想象一艘船，但里面是空的。
So then that's where you put the gravy in.
然后你就把肉汁放进去。
You pour it.
你倒它。
You can pour it.
你可以倒它。
All right, and so we can find that.
好的，所以我们能找到那个。
We can also find serving dishes, which are basically big plates or bowls that we use
我们还能找到上菜盘，基本上是我们
when we're having dinner at the dinner table to keep, for example, a turkey or a roast.
在餐桌上吃饭时用的大盘子或碗，用来盛放比如火鸡或烤肉。
And specifically we were also looking for wine glasses.
具体来说，我们还在找酒杯。
Well, maybe we weren't looking for them, but they found us because the person getting stuff
嗯，也许不是我们在找它们，而是它们找到了我们，因为那个从橱柜里拿东西的人
out of the cupboard dropped some wine glasses.
打碎了一些酒杯。
These are very, very easy to break.
这些非常非常容易碎。
Wine glasses are basically just glasses that maybe are tall and you drink wine out of them.
酒杯基本上就是那种可能很高的杯子，你用来喝葡萄酒。
That's right.
没错。
So there are specific type of glass usually used to drink wine.
所以有一种特定类型的杯子通常用来喝葡萄酒。
So wine glasses, I guess a normal glass that you use to drink maybe juice or water is just
所以酒杯，我想你用来喝果汁或水的普通杯子就只是
called a glass.
叫杯子。
Right.
对。
So you can't use a wine glass only when you're drinking wine.
所以你不能只在喝葡萄酒时才用酒杯。
Okay.
好的。
So we've taken a look at a lot of vocab here, a lot of tools that we use at the dinner table
所以我们在这里看了很多词汇，很多我们在餐桌上吃饭时用的工具。
when we're having dinner.
当我们吃饭时。
So let's listen to the dialogue again and review.
所以让我们再听一遍对话并复习。
Honey, can you set the table?
亲爱的，你能摆一下桌子吗？
Sure.
当然。
What are we having for dinner?
我们晚餐吃什么？
Do I need to put anything out in particular?
我需要特别摆出什么东西吗？
Well, make sure to put out the pepper and salt shakers.
嗯，记得摆出胡椒和盐瓶。
I don't know if your brother is coming tonight.
我不知道你弟弟今晚会不会来。
So set an extra place mat just in case.
所以多放一个餐垫以防万一。
Okay.
好的。
Should I use the fancy silverware?
我应该用那套精致的银器吗？
Yeah, go ahead.
嗯，用吧。
Forks, spoons, and knives.
叉子、勺子和刀子。
I roasted some meat, so be sure to put out some steak knives as well.
我烤了一些肉，所以记得也摆出牛排刀。
I'll also set some cups and saucers for some coffee after dinner.
我还会摆一些杯子和碟子，用来饭后喝咖啡。
Honey, have you seen our soup bowls?
亲爱的，你看到我们的汤碗了吗？
They're in the cupboard where you keep the gravy boat and serving dishes.
它们在放肉汁船和上菜盘的橱柜里。
Just be careful because the wine glasses are also the...
小心点，因为酒杯也在……
Oops.
哎呀。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now we have four key phrases that we've prepared for you on Fluency Builder.
所以现在我们有四个关键短语，我们在流利度构建器中为你准备好了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay.
好的。
So this first phrase is very important, especially as a child.
所以第一个短语非常重要，尤其是对孩子来说。
Your mother or father might ask you to do this.
你的妈妈或爸爸可能会让你做这个。
The phrase is to set the table.
这个短语是“set the table”。
Okay.
好的。
So that's a phrasal verb, to set the table.
所以这是一个动词短语，“set the table”。
And what does it mean if you're asked to set the table?
如果有人让你“set the table”，那是什么意思？
It means you will put down the plates and the silverware and the bowls so that everything
意思是你把盘子、银器和碗放好，这样一切
is prepared for dinner.
都为晚餐准备好了。
Okay.
好的。
So this is actually what we were doing and a complementary phrasal verb to this.
所以这实际上是我们正在做的，还有一个互补的动词短语。
When you're setting the table, as you said, you are putting down or putting out the different
当你“set the table”时，就像你说的，你是在放下或摆出不同的
spoons, knives, dishes, all that stuff.
勺子、刀子、盘子等等。
Right.
对。
So the verbal phrase to put out means to place down or to make sure that you get something
所以动词短语“put out”意思是放下或确保你把某样东西
out on the table.
摆到桌子上。
In this case, my mother would usually ask me to put out extra glasses for water.
在这种情况下，我妈妈通常会让我摆出额外的水杯。
Okay.
好的。
Or don't forget to put out the wine glasses in case we're drinking wine.
或者别忘了摆出酒杯，以防我们喝葡萄酒。
It just means to place down.
它只是意味着放下。
Exactly.
没错。
So just remember that we use it because all these things, they're inside the cupboard.
所以只要记住，我们用它是因为这些东西都在橱柜里。
So you have to take them out.
所以你得把它们拿出来。
So you have to put them out on the table.
所以你得把它们摆在桌子上。
All right.
好的。
And sometimes we may have a guest or we may need an extra chair or an extra seat because
有时候我们可能有客人，或者需要多一把椅子或座位，因为
we are having company and the person in dialogue said to set an extra placemat just in case.
我们要招待客人，对话里的人说要多放一个餐垫以防万一。
Okay.
好的。
So placemat is basically a piece of plastic or maybe fabric that you put in front of a
所以餐垫基本上是一块塑料或布料，放在
person when they're at the table.
一个人坐在桌前时面前的位置。
So it's on the table and it's something that protects the table.
它放在桌子上，用来保护桌面。
So it's small.
它很小。
Everyone has one and the bowl and the silverware will go on top of that placemat.
每个人都有一个，碗和餐具会放在那个餐垫上面。
But it also indicates that that is where someone will sit.
但它也表明那是某人要坐的位置。
Okay.
好的。
So to set out or to set out an extra placemat means to prepare an extra place for someone
所以“set out”或“set out an extra placemat”意思是多准备一个位置给
else who will be coming.
要来的人。
So if you have a guest, for example, you'll set out an extra placemat for him or for her.
比如，如果你有客人，你会为他或她多放一个餐垫。
Okay.
好的。
So we can say set an extra placemat because this is by this we are referring that somebody
所以我们可以说“set an extra placemat”，因为这意味着
is going to sit down at the table or you can just simply say set an extra place for someone.
有人要坐下吃饭，或者你可以简单地说“set an extra place for someone”。
That's right.
没错。
Set an extra place.
多准备一个位置。
Your older brother is coming home from college tonight.
你哥哥今晚从大学回家。
Okay.
好的。
So you set an extra place for him at the table.
所以你在桌上给他多准备一个位置。
And well, in this case, we didn't know if the brother was really coming or not.
嗯，在这个例子里，我们不确定哥哥是不是真的会来。
So she said just in case.
所以她说“以防万一”。
This is a great phrase, one that you'll hear all the time.
这是个很棒的短语，你会经常听到。
It means I'm not sure what the result will be or what the outcome will be.
它的意思是我不确定结果会怎样。
But in case something happens or just in case we should do this.
但以防万一发生什么事，或者为了保险起见，我们应该这样做。
So for example, Marco, I think it's going to rain today.
比如，Marco，我觉得今天会下雨。
You should bring an umbrella just in case.
你应该带把伞以防万一。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a way of saying you're preventing something.
所以这是一种预防的说法。
You're prepared.
你做好了准备。
Maybe if it does rain, you'll have an umbrella just in case.
如果真下雨了，你就有伞以防万一。
Bring your umbrella.
带上你的伞。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of great phrases there.
所以这里有很多好短语。
A lot of vocab.
很多词汇。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue for the last time.
那我们最后再听一遍对话吧。
Honey, can you set the table?
亲爱的，你能摆一下桌子吗？
Sure.
当然。
What are we having for dinner?
我们晚饭吃什么？
Do I need to put anything out in particular?
我需要特别摆什么东西出来吗？
Well, make sure to put out the pepper and salt shakers.
嗯，记得把胡椒瓶和盐瓶拿出来。
I don't know if your brother is coming tonight.
我不知道你哥哥今晚会不会来。
So set an extra placemat just in case.
所以多放一个餐垫以防万一。
Okay.
好的。
Should I use the fancy silverware?
我要用那套精致的餐具吗？
Yeah, go ahead.
嗯，用吧。
Forks, spoons, and knives.
叉子、勺子和刀子。
I roasted some meat, so be sure to put out some steak knives as well.
我烤了些肉，所以一定要也拿出几把牛排刀。
I'll also set some cups and saucers for some coffee after dinner.
我还会放几个杯子和碟子，饭后喝咖啡用。
Honey, have you seen our soup bowls?
亲爱的，你看到我们的汤碗了吗？
They're in the cupboard where you keep the gravy boat and serving dishes.
它们在放肉汁壶和上菜盘的橱柜里。
Just be careful because the wine glasses are also there.
小心点，因为酒杯也在那里。
Oops.
哎呀。
I'll be right back.
我马上回来。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So talking about dinner and silverware, there are also a couple of other names that we didn't
说到晚餐和餐具，还有几个我们没提到的
mention.
名称。
For example, many people refer to ceramic plates as china.
比如，很多人把陶瓷盘子称为“china”。
Yeah, these are usually the fancy kinds of plates and dishes that you have in your house.
是的，这通常是你家里那种精致的盘子和碗。
Obviously, if you have just kind of the cheap ceramics that you can throw away or even paper
显然，如果你只有那种便宜的陶瓷，可以扔掉的那种，甚至纸盘，
plates, those aren't very important.
那些就不太重要。
But at a wedding or in a special occasion, a person or a family might receive chinaware,
但在婚礼或特殊场合，一个人或家庭可能会收到瓷器，
china.
也就是“china”。
And that is very nice, very pretty porcelain plates or just lacquerware.
那是非常漂亮、精美的瓷盘或漆器。
Okay, so you can call it chinaware, which is basically plates that are either very fine
好的，所以你可以叫它“chinaware”，基本上就是非常精细的
ceramic or porcelain, as you said.
陶瓷或瓷器，就像你说的。
That's right.
没错。
Or what was the other word that you said before?
或者你之前说的另一个词是什么？
Lacquerware.
漆器。
Lacquerware is a certain kind of plate or ceramic that has a kind of sheen to it.
漆器是一种有光泽的盘子或陶瓷。
It's very special, kind of basically paint job.
它很特别，基本上是一种涂漆工艺。
Oh, okay.
哦，好的。
Yeah, because it's always been kind of strange the fact that a name like china would also
是啊，因为“china”这个名字现在也跟盘子有关，这总是有点奇怪。
now be related to plates.
没错。
But apparently, I guess because Chinese porcelain is renowned as being such high quality, I
但显然，我猜是因为中国瓷器以高品质闻名，所以
guess this is why now we just have a word for it called china or chinaware.
我想这就是为什么我们现在用“china”或“chinaware”这个词来称呼它。
I think it actually has to do with the fact that the Chinese in the old days sold, well,
我觉得这其实和古代中国人卖瓷器有关，嗯，
most of the British bought their porcelain from China.
大多数英国人都是从中国购买瓷器的。
And so it was very, very in vogue, it was very popular.
所以它非常、非常流行，非常受欢迎。
And it was basically the only thing that the British wanted.
而且基本上这是英国人唯一想要的东西。
They just wanted all of this china.
他们只想要所有这些瓷器。
And it became a part of the vocabulary then.
然后这就成了词汇的一部分。
Yeah, it's really strange though that you would call something china.
是啊，不过把某样东西叫做“china”真的很奇怪。
It's like, I don't know any other country that you call something, you know, like French.
就像，我不知道还有哪个国家你会用类似“French”来称呼东西。
This is a French or Frenchware.
比如“French”或“Frenchware”。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I can't think of any.
我想不出任何例子。
Limoges is the name of a city in France and it's a certain kind of ceramics.
利摩日是法国的一个城市名，它是一种特定的陶瓷。
Oh, there you go.
哦，这就对了。
All right.
好吧。
So an interesting topic.
所以这是个有趣的话题。
There are many other tools that we didn't mention like salad fork and ice cream spoon.
还有很多其他餐具我们没提到，比如沙拉叉和冰淇淋勺。
I don't know.
我不知道。
And sometimes if you go to a fancy dinner, you will have maybe three spoons, three knives,
有时候如果你去高档餐厅，你可能会看到三把勺子、三把刀、
three forks and you don't know what to do with it.
三把叉子，你不知道该怎么用。
Start on the outside and go in.
从最外面的开始，往里用。
That's my one recommendation.
这是我唯一的建议。
Exactly.
没错。
So we're really curious to know what you have to say.
所以我们很想知道你有什么看法。
Come to our website EnglishPod.com.
来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
If you have any questions, you can leave them there.
如果你有任何问题，可以在那里留言。
Or if you also want to suggest a topic for a lesson or anything you want, just let us
或者如果你想建议一个课程主题或任何你想要的东西，就告诉我们
know.
吧。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you then.
那我们到时候见。
All right.
好的。
Bye.
再见。